♪Minum ibun♪
♪미눔 이분♪
♪Your roots are holding tight♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 굳건히 자리잡고 있습니다♪
♪On this land♪
♪이 땅에서♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪멘게자르 옴박♪
♪My leaves fly by♪
♪나의 나뭇잎이 날아간다♪
♪The border of thousands of stones♪
♪수천개의 돌의 경계♪
♪Looking at each other from afar♪
♪멀리서 서로를 바라보며♪
♪The edge of the cliff is♪
♪절벽의 끝은♪
♪Live together forever♪
♪영원히 함께 살아요♪
♪When we meet and part again♪
♪만나고 또 헤어지면♪
♪When we depend on each other and are far away♪
♪서로 의지 하고 멀리 떨어져 있을 때♪
♪I never forget♪
♪절대 잊지 않아요♪
♪The light reflected on the sword and knife♪
♪검과 칼에 반사되는 빛♪
♪Light up the dim sky♪
♪어두운 하늘을 밝혀주세요♪
♪Abandoned dreams♪
♪버려진 꿈♪
♪Shattered in the wind♪
♪바람에 부서지네♪
♪Against the direction of the wind and waves♪
♪바람과 파도의 반대방향♪
♪See thousands of ships crossing♪
♪수천 척의 배가 건너가는 모습을 보세요♪
♪This world changes♪
♪이 세상은 변한다♪
♪A suit of armor with make-up swinging in the wind♪
♪화장한 갑옷이 바람에 휘날리네요♪
♪Drinking ice, the blood is hard to be cold, dreaming of having fun in love♪
♪얼음을 마시고 피가 식지 않고 즐거운 사랑을 꿈꾸며♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪ 당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요 ♪
♪Don't waste spring time♪
♪봄날을 낭비하지 마세요♪
♪Trees reach the sky, roots connect, your friends uphold justice in the world♪
♪나무는 하늘에 닿고, 뿌리는 연결되고, 친구들은 세상의 정의를 수호합니다♪
♪Seeing the light flickering on the shoulder♪
♪어깨에 깜빡이는 빛을 보고♪
♪No regrets in this world♪
♪세상에 후회는 없어♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=사랑의 원더랜드=
=Episode 23=
=에피소드 23=
Ayah.
유모.
I offered a drink to say congratulations to my father.
나는 아버지께 축하 인사를 전하기 위해 음료수를 권했습니다 .
After drinking,
술을 마신 후,
me and Ying will
나랑 Ying이 그럴 거야
get married
결혼하다
Drink it.
마셔보세요.
The commander-in-chief is aware.
총사령관은 알고 있습니다.
Of.
의.
Good.
좋은.
He was aware.
그는 알고 있었습니다.
Commander.
사령관.
Controller.
제어 장치.
Bind this rebellious child.
이 반항적인 아이를 묶으십시오.
Commander.
사령관.
The poison in the father's body has not been offered.
아버지의 몸에 있는 독은 바쳐지지 않았습니다.
He was still confused.
그는 여전히 혼란스러웠다.
Controller.
제어 장치.
Send him back to the room.
그를 다시 방으로 보내세요.
- Young master.
- 젊은 스승님.
Rebellious child.
반항적인 아이.
Didn't think so
그렇게 생각하지 않았어
you will mistreat father.
너는 아버지를 학대할 것이다.
Young master!
젊은 주인님!
Be careful, commander-in-chief!
조심하세요, 총사령관님!
Great Commander!
위대한 사령관!
Young master!
젊은 주인님!
What is the reason?
이유는 무엇입니까?
Are there any misunderstandings?
오해가 있나요?
Yes, young master.
응, 젊은 주인님.
This is the commander in chief, young master.
이 분은 총사령관이십니다, 젊은 스승님.
The commander-in-chief was confused.
총사령관은 혼란스러워졌습니다.
Quickly grab his sword
빨리 검을 잡아라
so that he doesn't hurt himself.
그 사람이 다치지 않도록.
Dream it.
꿈을 꾸세요.
He is the commander in chief.
그는 총사령관입니다.
Be careful, commander-in-chief!
조심하세요, 총사령관님!
Great Commander!
위대한 사령관!
Young master!
젊은 주인님!
Are there any misunderstandings?
오해가 있나요?
Great Commander!
위대한 사령관!
Who dares to hurt the commander-in-chief?
누가 감히 총사령관에게 상처를 주겠습니까?
Be careful!
조심하세요!
We will get married later.
우리는 나중에 결혼할 거예요.
Don't hurt my wife.
내 아내를 해치지 마세요.
who is your wife
당신의 아내는 누구입니까?
Shu, stop!
슈, 그만해!
Orang Jieshuo.
오랑제숴.
The young master let the Jieshuo people sneak in on the pretext of marriage.
젊은 스승은 결혼을 핑계로 Jieshuo 사람들을 몰래 들여보냈습니다 .
We trusted him in vain.
우리는 그를 헛되이 믿었습니다.
Young Master Cui.
젊은 스승 최.
Do not try to escape.
탈출을 시도하지 마십시오.
Mr. Shiqi has already said.
Shiqi 씨는 이미 말했습니다.
Yes
예
not Young Master Cui.
최영선생이 아닙니다.
Namanya Liu Chengfeng.
나만야 류청펑.
It's not wrong to call him Tuan Muda Cui.
그를 Tuan Muda Cui라고 부르는 것은 잘못된 것이 아닙니다 .
Now, he was still disguising himself as Young Master Cui.
이제 그는 여전히 최소사로 변장하고 있었습니다.
Namun, namanya Liu Chengfeng.
그냥, 나만야 Liu Chengfeng.
Young Master Cui.
젊은 스승 최.
Liu Chengfeng.
류청펑.
Liu Cheng...
류청...
Rebellious child.
반항적인 아이.
How dare you conspire with the Jieshuo people.
감히 Jieshuo 사람들과 공모합니까?
Have you
당신은
forget
잊다
Cui Family revenge?
추이 가문의 복수?
Cui Yi!
추이!
The situation has become like this.
상황은 이렇게 되었습니다.
Do not pretend
그런 척 하지마
be a loving father.
사랑하는 아버지가 되십시오.
I asked you.
나는 당신에게 물었다.
Have you ever been sincere?
진심이었던 적이 있나요?
You once considered me
당신은 한때 나를 고려했습니다
as your own child sincerely?
진심으로 자기 자식처럼?
You're just using me.
당신은 나를 이용하고 있어요.
What does it matter?
그것은 무슨 상관이야?
grudge between the Cui Family and Jieshuo
Cui Family와 Jieshuo 사이의 원한
with me?
나랑?
Okay.
좋아요.
I have no son.
나는 아들이 없습니다.
I only have one daughter.
나에겐 딸이 하나뿐이다.
Ying.
잉.
You don't have to
그럴 필요는 없습니다.
keep your identity a secret again.
당신의 신원을 다시 비밀로 유지하십시오.
All.
모두.
This is my daughter.
내딸이야.
He is the real Cui Lin.
그는 진짜 추이린이다.
He too
그도 마찬가지
using the name Cui Lin
Cui Lin이라는 이름을 사용하여
in a military camp.
군사 캠프에서.
I also always considered him as my own son.
나는 또한 항상 그를 내 아들로 여겼습니다.
Today, he brought in our enemies
오늘 그는 우리의 적을 데려왔다
and don't want to be my child anymore.
그리고 더 이상 내 아이가 되고 싶지 않아요.
So,
그래서,
I only have one daughter.
나에겐 딸이 하나뿐이다.
Cui Lin
추이린
my only child
내 하나뿐인 아이
However, he is greater
그러나 그는 더 위대하다
of men in this world.
이 세상 남자들의.
Liu Chengfeng.
류청펑.
Since you colluded with Jieshuo,
당신이 Jieshuo와 공모했기 때문에
poison me,
나를 독살해,
rebel and bring in enemies,
반란을 일으키고 적을 끌어들이고,
you are unfaithful, immoral and disobedient.
당신은 신실하지 않고 부도덕하며 불순종합니다.
Your crime has been revealed.
당신의 범죄가 밝혀졌습니다.
Give up quickly!
빨리 포기하세요!
You remember
당신은 기억합니다
can you catch me today?
오늘 나 좀 잡아줄래?
There is a blue light on the arrow head.
화살촉에 파란색 빛이 있습니다 .
Presumably it was coated with poison.
아마도 독으로 코팅되어 있었을 것입니다.
Li Ni.
리니.
Your identity limits you
당신의 정체성은 당신을 제한합니다
to bring in the military.
군대를 데려오려고.
You are just a few people
당신은 단지 소수의 사람일 뿐입니다
can catch me?
나를 잡을 수 있을까?
I want to kill you.
나는 당신을 죽이고 싶다.
- Dad! - Commander in chief!
- 아빠! - 총사령관!
Dad, are you okay?
아빠, 괜찮아요?
It's fine.
괜찮아.
Do not worry.
걱정 하지마.
The Zhenxi army was outside the city.
Zhenxi 군대는 도시 밖에있었습니다.
If we fight again,
또 싸우면,
both parties will definitely suffer huge losses.
양측 모두 분명히 큰 손실을 입을 것입니다.
Lepaskan Liu Chengfeng.
레파스칸 류청펑.
Go away from here!
여기서 떠나세요!
Shiqi.
시치.
Your men are hiding to ambush outside the city.
당신의 부하들은 도시 밖에서 매복 공격을 하기 위해 숨어 있습니다 .
Liu Chengfeng had already brought people out of the city.
Liu Chengfeng은 이미 사람들을 도시 밖으로 데리고 나갔습니다.
You can attack them.
당신은 그들을 공격할 수 있습니다.
Slowly.
느리게.
Ayah.
유모.
I told Taozi to check dad's pulse.
나는 Taozi에게 아빠의 맥박을 확인하라고 말했습니다.
No need.
필요 없음.
Dad, it's okay.
아빠, 괜찮아요.
Taozi has already said.
Taozi는 이미 말했습니다.
He himself provided this antidote.
그는 스스로 해독제를 제공했습니다.
Poison will be offered slowly.
독은 천천히 제공됩니다 .
It's good, father, don't fight.
좋아요, 아버지, 싸우지 마세요.
When father found out this was the crime of the disobedient son,
아버지는 이것이 불순종한 아들의 죄임을 알았을 때 ,
Dad couldn't help himself.
아빠는 스스로를 도울 수 없었습니다.
I didn't think he conspired with Jieshuo.
나는 그가 Jieshuo와 공모했다고 생각하지 않았습니다 .
He knew the Cui Family
그는 Cui 가족을 알고 있었어요
berdendam dengan Jieshuo.
berdendam dengan Jieshuo.
I don't know why
왜인지 모르겠어요
he became like this.
그는 이렇게 되었습니다.
It was in vain that his father thought of him as his biological son
그의 아버지가 그를 생물학적 아들로 생각한 것은 헛된 일이었습니다.
many years.
수년.
Ayah,
유모,
don't be sad anymore.
더 이상 슬퍼하지 마세요.
Ying,
잉,
after your father and mother have been married for ten years,
네 아버지와 어머니가 결혼한 지 10년이 지나면
you were just born.
당신은 방금 태어났습니다.
Although father announced
아버지가 발표했지만
you are a man
당신은 남자입니다
so that the government does not grant the father another wife,
정부가 그 아버지에게 다른 아내를 주지 않도록
your father and mother
너의 아버지와 어머니
have a selfish mind,
이기적인 마음을 갖고 ,
that is, we want to leave everything in the Cui Family
즉, 우리는 Cui Family에 모든 것을 남기고 싶습니다.
to you.
당신에게.
Only sons are important in this world.
이 세상에서는 오직 아들만이 중요합니다.
No daughter ever inherits the family property,
어떤 딸도 가족 재산을 상속받지 못하며,
especially in the military.
특히 군대에서는요.
We announce you are a boy
우리는 당신이 남자임을 발표합니다
for you
당신을 위한
can have everything in the Cui Family.
Cui Family의 모든 것을 가질 수 있습니다.
I understand, father.
이해해요, 아버지.
Ever since I was sensible,
내가 현명했을 때부터,
father told me
아버지가 나에게 말씀하셨어
about this clearly.
이것에 대해서는 분명히.
This is my choice too.
이것도 내 선택이다.
I don't find it difficult.
나는 그것이 어렵다고 생각하지 않습니다.
Sadly.
슬프게도.
Sama ada Liu Chengfeng
사마 아다 리우 청펑
or Cui Li,
또는 추이 리,
how nice
얼마나 좋은지
if they can help you.
그들이 당신을 도울 수 있다면.
The human mind is unpredictable.
인간의 마음은 예측할 수 없습니다.
Even though dad was alert,
아빠가 조심했어도
appear
나타나다
a traitor at last.
드디어 배신자.
Ayah.
유모.
Dad has done a lot for me.
아빠는 나에게 많은 일을 해주셨다 .
Ying.
잉.
Dad revealed your identity today.
오늘 아빠가 네 정체를 공개했어 .
I am afraid that many more problems will be caused in the future.
앞으로는 더 많은 문제가 발생할까 두렵습니다 .
I know you are wise and do not hesitate.
나는 당신이 현명하다는 것을 알고 주저하지 않습니다.
You are better than anyone else.
당신은 누구보다 낫습니다.
As a father,
아버지로서,
Dad is still worried.
아빠는 아직도 걱정이 많으세요.
If dad doesn't take good care of you,
아빠가 잘 돌봐주지 않으면
What kind of
어떤 종류의
father want to face your late mother later?
아버지, 돌아가신 어머니를 나중에 만나고 싶나요 ?
Ayah,
유모,
do not worry.
걱정 하지마.
I am my father's son.
나는 아버지의 아들입니다.
Although many problems will befall me,
나에게 많은 문제가 닥치 겠지만 ,
finished?
완성된?
I am
그래요
will not be shackled by the worldly.
세상 사람들의 얽매이지 않을 것입니다.
Good to say you.
말씀드리니 반갑습니다.
Now it's different.
이제는 달라졌습니다.
Even though everyone
다들 그렇지만
find our clause,
우리 조항을 찾아보세요,
we are children
우리는 아이들이다
no need to be afraid
두려워할 필요 없어
Of.
의.
Don't worry, dad.
걱정하지 마세요, 아빠.
Greetings to the young lady.
젊은 아가씨에게 인사드립니다.
Greetings to the commanders.
지휘관들에게 인사드립니다.
During the old days,
옛날에는
the government insists on giving me another wife
정부는 나에게 다른 아내를 주겠다고 고집한다
because I have no children.
왜냐하면 나는 아이가 없기 때문입니다.
The love between me and my wife is deep.
나와 아내 사이의 사랑은 깊습니다.
After we gave birth to a daughter,
우리는 딸을 낳은 후 ,
I said I got a son.
아들이 생겼다고 하더군요 .
Then, the situation in the draw changed.
그러다가 추첨 상황이 달라졌다.
So, I didn't tell you
그래서, 내가 너한테 말하지 않았어
about the truth.
진실에 대해.
Actually, Cui Lin is my only daughter.
사실 추이린은 나의 외동딸이에요.
Oh it's like that.
아 그렇군요.
Even if you are young
어린데도
holding the position of lieutenant only,
단지 중위의 직위를 갖고 있으며,
we watched
우리는 보았다
his personal performance.
그의 개인적인 성과.
Women are equal to men.
여성은 남성과 동등합니다.
We will definitely try our best to help him.
우리는 그를 돕기 위해 최선을 다할 것입니다 .
We will definitely obey.
우리는 반드시 순종할 것입니다.
Don't worry, commander in chief.
걱정하지 마세요, 총사령관님.
Me and Junior Commander Pei
나와 페이 중령
hide outside the city according to your instructions.
당신의 지시에 따라 성 밖에 숨어 지내십시오 .
Kami memang nampak Liu Chengfeng
Kami memang nampak Liu Chengfeng
membawa orang Jieshuo.
membawa orang Jieshuo.
We ambushed him when he was not ready.
그가 준비되지 않았을 때 우리는 그를 매복 공격했습니다 .
However,
하지만,
their poison is too great.
그들의 독이 너무 크다.
Even though many people are attacked,
많은 사람들이 공격을 당해도
Liu Chengfeng
리우 청펑
still managed to escape.
그래도 탈출에 성공했습니다.
He's lost his mind.
그는 정신을 잃었습니다.
In fact, he conspired with the enemy.
사실 그는 적과 공모했습니다.
Jieshuo pandai menggunakan racun.
Jieshuo panda menggunakan racun.
Later, we must be careful.
나중에는 조심해야 합니다.
Of.
의.
That's Lieutenant He, right?
그 사람이 중위 맞죠?
Not.
아니다.
Young Miss Cui has arrived.
Young Miss Cui가 도착했습니다.
Young Miss Cui is already struggling.
Young Miss Cui는 이미 어려움을 겪고 있습니다.
Brother Bao is already struggling.
바오 형제는 이미 어려움을 겪고 있습니다.
We are our own people.
우리는 우리 자신의 사람들입니다.
Tentera Zhenxi
텐테라 젠시
willing to help Ms. Young Cui eliminate the enemy.
Young Cui 씨가 적을 제거하도록 기꺼이 도와줍니다 .
I circulated first.
제가 먼저 유통했어요.
The young lady and Mr. Shiqi are chatting.
젊은 아가씨와 Shiqi 씨가 이야기를 나누고 있습니다.
Fortunately you are here today.
다행히도 당신은 오늘 여기에 있습니다.
We are our own people.
우리는 우리 자신의 사람들입니다.
Tentera Zhenxi
텐테라 젠시
willing to help Ms. Young Cui eliminate the enemy.
Young Cui 씨가 적을 제거하도록 기꺼이 도와줍니다 .
I'm willing too.
나도 기꺼이.
Brash mouth.
뻔뻔스러운 입.
Bao said earlier,
보아는 앞서 말했다.
they had already wiped out many Jieshuo people.
그들은 이미 많은 Jieshuo 사람들을 몰살시켰습니다 .
However, Liu Chengfeng managed to escape.
그러나 Liu Chengfeng은 탈출에 성공했습니다.
Tak sangka Liu Chengfeng bersubahat dengan Jieshuo.
Tak sangka Liu Chengfeng bersubahat dengan Jieshuo.
Keluarga Cui dan Jieshuo
켈루아르가 추이 단 지에슈오
hold a grudge
원한을 품다
From now on,
지금부터,
he's not my brother anymore
그 사람은 이제 내 동생이 아니야
He is an enemy of the Cui Family.
그는 Cui Family의 적입니다.
I shouldn't say that,
그런 말을 하면 안 되는데,
But
하지만
after hearing this, i feel relieved.
이 말을 듣고 나니 마음이 편해졌습니다.
You haven't told me yet.
당신은 아직 나에게 말하지 않았습니다.
How did you find out my father was poisoned.
우리 아버지가 독살되었다는 걸 어떻게 알았나요 ?
How did you find it?
어떻게 찾았나요?
rancangan Liu Chengfeng
랜칸안 리우 청펑
and cooperate with my father?
그리고 우리 아버지한테 협력해?
After I returned to camp,
캠프로 돌아온 후,
I thought about this.
나는 이것에 대해 생각했다.
The more I think, the more I feel there is something unfamiliar.
생각할수록 뭔가 낯설다는 느낌이 듭니다.
So, Taozi and I sneaked into the Cui Residence
그래서 Taozi와 나는 Cui Residence에 몰래 들어갔습니다.
to investigate the commander-in-chief
총사령관을 조사하기 위해
exposed to what poison?
어떤 독에 노출됐나요?
Er Duo, control it well so that other people don't notice.
어 듀오, 다른 사람들이 눈치채지 못하도록 잘 조절하세요 .
Taozi is very confident
Taozi는 매우 자신감이 있습니다
Panglima besar terkena racun Jieshuo.
Panglima besar terkena racun Jieshuo.
Kebetulan awak terkena racun Jieshuo juga.
Kebetulan awak terkena racun Jieshuo juga.
At that time, you saw Liu Chengfeng.
그 당시 Liu Chengfeng을 보았습니다.
So, I suspect
그래서 나는 의심한다.
the incident of the commander-in-chief being poisoned has something to do with him.
총사령관이 독살된 사건은 그와 관련이 있다.
At first, the commander-in-chief
처음에는 총사령관이
refused to believe it.
그것을 믿기를 거부했습니다.
Until then,
그때까지,
he found it was indeed his crime.
그는 그것이 실제로 그의 범죄라는 것을 알았습니다.
My father was very sad.
아버지는 매우 슬펐습니다.
my lord
군주
No need to be so polite.
그렇게 예의바르게 대할 필요는 없습니다.
Do you know about it?
당신은 그것에 대해 알고 있나요?
I mean my lord...
내 말은, 주인님...
Everyone knows that
다들 그걸 알아
Cui Yi
추이
have a son.
아들이 있어요.
(Empress, Lu) Try to guess what happened.
(루황후) 무슨 일이 일어났는지 추측해 보세요.
This boy is not his.
이 소년은 그의 것이 아니다.
Not his son?
그의 아들이 아닌가요?
That's right.
좋아요.
He has only one daughter.
그는 딸이 하나뿐입니다.
Since childhood, he was raised as a boy.
어린 시절부터 그는 소년으로 자랐습니다.
His daughter disguised herself as a man
그의 딸이 남자로 변장했다.
and served in the Cui Family Army.
Cui Family Army에서 복무했습니다 .
Apparently, he is famous.
분명히 그는 유명합니다.
What's his name?
무슨 일이 그의 이름이다?
Leftenan He.
레프테난 그.
I didn't think something like this existed.
나는 이런 것이 존재한다고 생각하지 않았습니다.
Cui Yi
추이
cheating beta
부정 행위 베타
However, the employees at the hall said seriously,
그러나 홀의 직원들은 진지하게 말했다.
Cui Yi is very powerful.
Cui Yi는 매우 강력합니다.
Furthermore, Sun Jing
게다가 쑨징은
not dead and still conquering the Tong Border,
죽지 않고 여전히 통 국경을 정복하고 있으며,
an important military base.
중요한 군사기지.
Again,
다시,
Cui Yi merampas
추이 메람파스
Changzhou now.
지금 창저우.
So, the officers
그래서 간부들은
advise beta
베타에게 조언하다
to calm Cui Yi's heart.
최이의 마음을 진정시키기 위해.
A good idea
좋은 아이디어
crossed my mind.
내 마음을 넘어.
My lord wants...
주인님이 원하시는데...
Cui Yi doesn't have a son, right?
최이에게는 아들이 없지요?
Beta helps him find an adoptive child.
베타는 그가 입양아를 찾는 데 도움을 줍니다.
Until then,
그때까지,
The Cui family has an heir.
Cui 가족에게는 상속인이 있습니다.
So, Commander Cui
알아요, 추이 사령관
will listen to beta instructions later.
나중에 베타 지침을 듣게 될 것입니다.
my lord
군주
Who do you want to choose as the heir of the Cui Family?
추이 가문의 후계자로 누구를 선택하고 싶나요 ?
That's why I came to meet my sister.
그래서 언니를 만나러 왔어요.
Beta wants to choose one
베타는 하나를 선택하고 싶어합니다
from your sister's niece
네 여동생의 조카에게서
to become the adopted son of the Cui Family.
추이 가문의 양자가 되기 위해.
my lord,
군주,
I'm afraid this is not good.
이건 좋지 않은 것 같아요.
Why?
왜?
Don't you want to?
원하지 않습니까?
It's not that you don't want to.
당신이 원하지 않는 것이 아닙니다.
Try to think.
생각해보세요.
Cui Yi Panglima Besar Pingliang,
Cui Yi Panglima Besar Pingliang,
the commander in chief of the Cui Family Army.
추이 가문 군대의 총사령관.
In that year,
그해에는
he led an army to conquer Jieshuo.
그는 Jieshuo를 정복하기 위해 군대를 이끌었습니다 .
You have heard
당신은 들었다
the greatness of Commander-in-Chief Cui.
추이 총사령관의 위대함.
This kind of person
이런 사람
refused to retreat from Changzhou.
창저우에서 퇴각을 거부했다.
It is obvious that he cannot be controlled by the government.
그가 정부에 의해 통제 될 수 없다는 것은 명백하다 .
Even though my lord has good intentions
주인님의 뜻은 좋으나
to choose an heir for his side,
그의 편을 위한 상속자를 선택하기 위해,
sister worried about his opinion,
그의 의견이 걱정되는 여동생
my lord
군주
wanted to seize the Cui Family's property
Cui 가족의 재산을 압류하고 싶었습니다.
and military power against the Cui Family Army.
그리고 Cui Family Army에 대항하는 군사력 .
Beta really thinks so.
베타는 정말 그렇게 생각합니다.
After all.
결국.
There was no way Cui Yi could have guessed that.
Cui Yi가 그것을 추측할 수 있는 방법은 없었습니다.
Cui Yi had been leading the military for many years .
Cui Yi는 수년 동안 군대를 이끌었습니다.
He asked his daughter to disguise herself as a boy.
그는 딸에게 남자로 변장해 달라고 부탁했다.
In fact, his daughter is wise.
사실 그의 딸은 현명하다.
Now, he revealed this.
이제 그는 이것을 밝혔습니다.
It is impossible that he intended to find an heir.
그가 상속인을 찾으려고 했다는 것은 불가능합니다 .
Impossible
불가능한
he could not guess my master's thoughts.
그는 내 주인의 생각을 짐작할 수 없었습니다.
If so, how?
그렇다면 어떻게?
Should I accept Cui Yi's daughter ?
추이의 딸을 받아들여야 할까요 ?
as an adopted child?
입양아로서?
Then, appointed her as a princess.
그런 다음 그녀를 공주로 임명했습니다.
After she became a princess,
그녀는 공주가 된 후,
find him a husband who obeys his word?
그의 말에 순종하는 남편을 찾으시겠습니까 ?
Is it like this?
이런가요?
new beta can be ordered
새로운 베타를 주문할 수 있습니다
The Cui Family Army?
추이 가문 군대?
Cui Yi's daughter
추이의 딸
raised like a man.
남자처럼 자랐어요.
Presumably,
아마도,
he's not an ordinary person.
그는 평범한 사람이 아닙니다.
Sister is worried that she refuses to be a princess.
언니는 자신이 공주가 되는 것을 거부하는 것이 걱정된다 .
If she refuses to be a princess,
만약 그녀가 공주가 되기를 거부한다면,
what does he want to be?
그 사람은 무엇이 되고 싶어?
This is just a guess.
이것은 단지 추측일 뿐입니다.
If my lord has this plan,
내 주군이 이런 계획을 가지고 있다면,
It's good, sir, to send someone
선생님, 사람을 보내는 것이 좋습니다
to find out
알아내다
Young Miss Cui's thoughts.
Young Miss Cui의 생각.
See if she wants to be a princess.
그녀가 공주가 되고 싶어 하는지 살펴보세요 .
Ayah.
유모.
Sit down.
앉아.
In today's series hall,
오늘 시리즈 홀에서는
the occurrence of a matter.
문제의 발생.
Cui Lin, son of Cui Yi
추이의 아들 추이린
is a girl.
소녀입니다.
What?
무엇?
Cui Yi only has one daughter.
최이에게는 딸이 하나 뿐이다.
However, he lied
그러나 그는 거짓말을 했다
that she had a son,
그녀에게 아들이 있다는 것,
namely Cui Lin.
즉 추이린.
Later, he received an adopted child.
나중에 그는 입양아를 얻었다.
This adopted child
이 입양아
using the name Cui Lin.
Cui Lin이라는 이름을 사용합니다.
His daughter as well
그 딸도 그렇고
uses the surname He.
그는 He라는 성을 사용합니다.
He was famous in the Cui Family Army.
그는 Cui Family Army에서 유명했습니다.
He was known as Lieutenant He.
그는 허 중위로 알려졌습니다.
Apparently Lieutenant He
분명히 그 중위
Cui Yi's daughter.
추이의 딸.
It should be.
그것은해야한다.
Do you still remember?
아직도 기억하시나요?
Before this, the King of Qin
그 전에는 진왕(秦王)이
sneaked into the Capital City of Xichang
수도인 시창(西昌)에 잠입했다
to meet father at the silk shop,
비단가게에서 아버지를 만나러
person by his side
옆에 있는 사람
is Lieutenant He.
그 중위입니다.
In addition,
게다가,
Lieutenant He who helped the King of Qin
진왕을 도운 중위
plan the meeting.
회의를 계획하세요.
The girl is graceful
그 소녀는 우아하다
and wise.
그리고 현명하다.
He makes a deep impression on people.
그는 사람들에게 깊은 인상을 남깁니다.
Apparently she is Cui Yi's daughter.
분명히 그녀는 Cui Yi의 딸입니다.
Wan'niang.
완냥.
Dad knows
아빠는 알아요
you have big ambitions.
당신은 큰 야망을 가지고 있습니다.
Considering Cui Lin
추이린을 고려하다
Cui Yi's daughter,
추이의 딸,
King of Qin
진왕
maybe like him.
어쩌면 그 사람처럼.
Ayah
유모
will help me
나에게 도움이 될 것이다
You are so clever.
너 정말 똑똑하다.
Dad for sure
아빠는 꼭
try your best
최고의 노력을
to help you
당신을 돕기 위해
Cui Yi's daughter is not great either.
Cui Yi의 딸도 좋지 않습니다.
His father
그의 아버지
commander-in-chief wields military power.
총사령관이 군사력을 행사한다.
My father too
우리 아버지도
chief civil servants.
최고 공무원.
I just listen
난 그냥 들어요
the emperor was afraid of the border officials
황제는 국경관리들을 두려워했다
who holds military power,
군사력을 쥐고 있는 사람,
but never heard of it
하지만 들어본 적이 없어
the emperor is afraid of
황제는 두려워한다
gentle civil servant.
친절한 공무원.
Good to say you.
말씀드리니 반갑습니다.
Dad knows
아빠는 알아요
father's daughter
아버지의 딸
comparable to Cui Yi's daughter.
Cui Yi의 딸과 비슷합니다.
The young lady looks beautiful in this kind of dress.
그 젊은 아가씨는 이런 종류의 드레스를 입으니 정말 아름다워 보이네요 .
I'm just worried
걱정이 될 뿐이야
The young lady showed herself
젊은 아가씨가 모습을 드러냈어요
by wearing men's clothes.
남자 옷을 입으면서.
With clothes like this,
이런 옷으로,
will they feel
그들이 느낄까
not used to?
익숙하지 않아?
Now,
지금,
Dad already told everyone that
아빠는 이미 모든 사람에게 그렇게 말했어요
I am his only daughter.
나는 그의 외동딸이다.
In that case,
그 경우,
I have to show
보여줘야 해
my stripes
내 줄무늬
As his daughter,
그의 딸로서,
I will definitely make him proud.
나는 확실히 그를 자랑스럽게 만들 것입니다.
Hurry up and see.
서둘러서 확인해 보세요.
So beautiful.
너무 아름다워요.
Your taste is good.
당신의 취향은 좋습니다.
Very suitable for young lady's skin color.
젊은 여성의 피부색에 매우 적합합니다.
Li Ni greeted the commander-in-chief.
리니가 총사령관에게 인사했다.
What business does the King of Qin have?
진왕은 무슨 사업을 합니까?
Still about the Changzhou clause.
여전히 창저우 조항에 관한 것입니다.
I want to discuss the Changzhou clause
창저우 조항에 대해 논의하고 싶습니다.
with the commander in chief.
총사령관과 함께.
The new King of Qin
새로운 진왕
save me
구해줘
So,
그래서,
did you come to demand revenge?
복수를 요구하러 왔나요?
I don't dare to do that.
나는 감히 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
Who sent the letter?
누가 편지를 보냈나요?
to the Cui Family Army
추이 가문 군대에게
to save Pei Yuan?
페이 위안을 구하기 위해?
King Qin still remembers, right?
진왕은 아직도 기억하고 있죠?
The commander-in-chief held out his hand.
총사령관이 손을 내밀었다.
I am very grateful.
나는 매우 감사합니다.
However, things have changed.
그러나 상황이 바뀌었습니다.
The great commander conquered Changzhou.
대장군이 창저우(長州)를 정복하였다.
Not only criticized by the government,
정부의 비난뿐만 아니라
even the commander-in-chief needs to be wary of Sun Jing.
총사령관조차도 Sun Jing을 조심해야합니다.
After all,
결국,
distance between Changzhou and Luoyang,
창저우와 뤄양 사이의 거리,
Jianzhou, Bingzhou
지안저우, 빙저우
and a military camp in Pingliang
그리고 핑량(Pingliang)의 군사 캠프
quite far.
꽤 먼.
The Cui Family Army is here
Cui 가족 군대가 여기 있습니다
not even profitable.
수익성도 없습니다.
do you mean
무슨 뜻인가요?
Changzhou
창저우
useless
쓸모 없는
for me,
나를 위한,
is it ok if i return it to you?
내가 너한테 돌려줘도 괜찮아?
Great Commander.
위대한 사령관.
Why don't I change Luoyang and Changzhou
낙양과 창저우를 바꾸면 어떨까요?
dengan Weiyang?
덴안 웨이양?
What does King Qin mean?
진왕(秦王)은 무슨 뜻인가요?
Although Weiyang is not in my jurisdiction,
웨이양은 내 관할권이 아니지만 ,
Weiyang is located to the left of Pingliang.
웨이양(Weiyang)은 핑량(Pingliang)의 왼쪽에 위치해 있습니다 .
Civil and military affairs
민사 및 군사 업무
in my jurisdiction as Commander-in-Chief of Pingliang.
내 관할권에 있는 핑량(Pingliang)의 총사령관입니다.
You want to exchange my stuff
내 물건을 교환하고 싶어?
with my stuff?
내 물건으로?
In fact, you theorized.
사실, 당신은 이론을 세웠습니다.
Commander-in-chief needs real rights.
총사령관에게는 실질적인 권리가 필요합니다.
Although Weiyang is close to Pingliang,
웨이양은 핑량과 가깝지만,
there is an army
군대가 있다
the administrative center of Youzhou is based there.
Youzhou의 행정 중심지가 그곳에 있습니다.
If the hall gives a series of orders,
홀에서 일련의 명령을 내리면,
the great commander controlled Pingliang
위대한 사령관이 핑량(Pingliang)을 통제했습니다.
Dan Weiyang.
단 웨이양.
So, great commander
그러니 위대한 사령관이여
can control
통제할 수 있다
Pingliang's affairs
핑량의 일
and Weiyang officially.
공식적으로는 Weiyang입니다.
Later, the position of the Cui Family Army will be strong and there will be no worries.
나중에 최씨군의 지위가 확고해져서 걱정이 없을 것이다.
What does the commander in chief think?
총사령관은 어떻게 생각하시나요?
In that case,
그 경우,
as long as the ballroom is a draw
연회장이 무승부인 한
hand over Weiyang to me,
웨이양을 나에게 넘겨라.
I will withdraw from Changzhou.
나는 창저우에서 철수할 것이다.
However, I will not back down
그러나 나는 물러서지 않을 것이다.
from Luoyang.
낙양 출신.
The commander-in-chief's mind was firm.
총사령관의 마음은 확고했습니다.
Even though I feel all wrong,
내가 다 틀린 것 같아도
I will ask the Balairung Seri to issue the order immediately.
즉시 Balairung Seri에게 명령을 내리도록 요청하겠습니다 .
I will only bring up Changzhou.
저는 창저우만 언급하겠습니다.
Don't worry, commander in chief.
걱정하지 마세요, 총사령관님.
Okay.
좋아요.
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
After the Changzhou clause was settled,
창저우 조항이 확정된 후,
you can go back to the capital.
수도로 돌아갈 수 있습니다.
Great Commander.
위대한 사령관.
I have one more request.
요청이 하나 더 있습니다.
What is he?
그는 무엇입니까?
I would like to have Young Miss Cui lead the Cui Family Army
나는 추이 양이 추이 가문 군대를 이끌도록 하고 싶습니다.
go to the Tong Border with me
나랑 같이 통 보더(Tong Border)로 가세요
to eradicate Sun Jing.
Sun Jing을 근절하기 위해.
You want to ask my son
내 아들에게 물어보고 싶나요?
go against Sun Jing with you?
당신과 함께 Sun Jing을 상대할 건가요?
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
Your request
당신의 요청
too many.
너무 많아.
If Sun Jing is not eradicated,
손정이 근절되지 않으면
not only government officials,
공무원뿐만 아니라
even the commander-in-chief was worried.
총사령관도 걱정했다.
Originally, the commander-in-chief
원래는 총사령관이었어.
led the army to the south waving the army flag.
군기를 흔들며 군대를 남쪽으로 이끌었다 .
Now, the commander-in-chief is temporarily based in Changzhou
현재 총사령관은 임시로 창저우에 주둔하고 있다.
and defend Luoyang.
낙양을 방어하십시오.
Of course, the audience is buzzing.
물론 청중은 윙윙 거리고 있습니다.
As long as the commander-in-chief agrees the Cui Family Army and me
총사령관이 Cui Family Army와 나에게 동의하는 한
go to the Barrel Border
배럴 보더로 이동
to defeat Sun Jing and recapture the Tong Border,
손정을 물리치고 통국경을 탈환하기 위해
rumors in the draw hall
추첨실에 소문이 돌았어
will end.
끝날 것이다.
In fact, everyone
사실 다들
will praise the obedience of the commander-in-chief.
총사령관의 순종을 찬양할 것이다.
What if I don't agree?
동의하지 않으면 어떻게 되나요?
After I myself recaptured the Tong Border,
내가 통국경을 탈환한 후,
maybe a series hall
아마 시리즈 홀이겠지
will order me
나에게 명령할 것이다
to fight with the commander-in-chief.
총사령관과 싸우기 위해.
Until then,
그때까지,
I can't refuse it.
나는 그것을 거부할 수 없습니다.
Hall series
홀 시리즈
will definitely recapture Dongdu first.
반드시 동두를 먼저 탈환할 것이다.
Try the King of Qin.
진왕(秦王)을 시험해 보십시오.
I am
그래요
never fought with the King of Qin.
진왕과 싸운 적이 없다.
I would like to witness
나는 목격하고 싶다
the arrangement of the army of the King of Qin.
진왕의 군대 배치.
I don't want to
나는 원하지 않는다
hostile to the Cui Family Army.
Cui 가족 군대에 적대적입니다.
The commander-in-chief knows too.
총사령관도 알고 있다.
The border of Tong locks the two cities.
통의 국경은 두 도시를 잠급니다.
Besides the Barrel Border,
배럴 보더 외에도
there is no other place to defend these two cities.
이 두 도시를 방어 할 다른 곳은 없습니다 .
As long as the commander-in-chief agreed to the Cui Family Army
총사령관이 추이 가문 군대에 동의하는 한
go to the Tong Border with me,
나와 함께 통 국경(Tong Border)으로 가세요.
suspicion of the government
정부 의혹
against the Cui Family Army will be reduced.
Cui Family 군대에 대한 공격이 줄어들 것입니다.
Hopefully the commander-in-chief can fulfill this request.
총사령관이 이 요청을 이행할 수 있기를 바랍니다.
In that case,
그 경우,
My son does not need to go with you.
내 아들은 당신과 함께 갈 필요가 없습니다.
I went to the Tong Border with you.
나는 당신과 함께 통 국경 에 갔다 .
Indeed so.
실제로 그렇습니다.
Before this, I discussed with Ying.
그 전에 잉이랑 얘기를 나눴어요.
He told me.
그는 나에게 말했다.
Great Commander
위대한 사령관
will definitely say so.
분명히 그렇게 말할 것이다.
I asked Ying if it was appropriate for me to answer.
나는 Ying에게 대답하는 것이 적절한지 물었습니다.
Ying told me.
잉이 나에게 말했다.
Talk
말하다
he and I have reached an agreement.
그와 나는 합의에 도달했습니다.
He is willing to go with me.
그는 기꺼이 나와 함께 갈 의향이 있습니다.
If you have reached agreement,
합의에 이르렀다면,
why are you asking me again?
왜 나한테 또 묻는 거야?
Does this mean the commander-in-chief has agreed?
총사령관이 동의했다는 뜻인가요 ?
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다.
Who is your uncle?
당신의 삼촌은 누구입니까?
Go away from here!
여기서 떠나세요!
Of.
의.
Even though King Qin extended his hand this time,
이번에는 진왕이 손을 내밀었지만,
Tentera Zhenxi
텐테라 젠시
still yearning for Changzhou.
아직도 창저우를 그리워하고 있어요.
We need to be vigilant.
우리는 경계해야 합니다.
He is the emperor's son.
그는 황제의 아들이다.
He came because he received orders.
그는 명령을 받았기 때문에 왔다.
We cannot cooperate with him so easily.
우리는 그에게 그렇게 쉽게 협력할 수 없습니다 .
Ying.
잉.
There are many men in this world.
이 세상에는 많은 남자들이 있습니다.
Why do you admire him?
왜 그를 존경합니까?
Ayah.
유모.
He is worth my admiration.
그는 내가 존경할 만한 사람이다.
It is difficult to predict the situation now.
지금 상황은 예측하기 어렵다.
Even though Sun Jing lost, he was still at the Tong Border.
Sun Jing은 패했지만 여전히 Tong Border에 있었습니다.
The three princes compete with each other.
세 왕자가 서로 경쟁합니다.
The King of Qin has great merit and is easily overcome by problems.
진왕은 공덕이 커서 문제가 생기면 쉽게 굴복합니다.
Although King Qin is unmatched,
진왕은 타의 추종을 불허하지만
he is not an ideal partner.
그는 이상적인 파트너가 아닙니다.
Ying, you need to think hard
잉, 잘 생각해봐야 해
if you want to be with him.
그 사람과 함께 있고 싶다면.
Ayah.
유모.
I like Li Ni.
리니처럼.
He likes me too.
그 사람도 나를 좋아해요.
Although
하지만
there are many men in this world,
세상에는 남자가 많아요.
he's the only one
그 사람은 유일한 사람이야
can capture my heart.
내 마음을 사로잡을 수 있어요.
I only have you as a child.
나에겐 어린 시절의 당신밖에 없습니다.
Since you've already thought about cooking
이미 요리에 대해 생각해 보셨 기 때문에
and make decisions,
결정을 내리고,
I won't try to change your mind.
나는 당신의 마음을 바꾸려고 노력하지 않을 것입니다.
Thank you dad.
고마워요 아빠.
Mari.
마리.
- Drink.
- 마시다.
The young lady is educated and willing to fight.
그 젊은 아가씨는 교육을 받았으며 싸울 의지가 있습니다.
In fact, she is the daughter of the great commander.
사실 그녀는 위대한 사령관의 딸입니다.
In your opinion,
귀하의 의견으로는
who is worthy
누가 합당한가
be his partner?
그의 파트너가 되어줄래?
In my opinion,
내 생각에는,
The King of Qin suits.
진(秦)왕이 복을 입는다.
Since saving the emperor,
황제를 구한 이후부터
King Qin led the Zhenxi Army and never lost.
진왕은 진희군을 이끌었고 한 번도 패한 적이 없습니다.
Put other things aside.
다른 것들은 제쳐두세요.
He is a rare commander-in-chief
그는 보기 드문 총사령관이다.
in the war on the Tong Border.
통 국경 전쟁에서.
Although King Qin was brilliant,
진왕은 비록 훌륭했지만
he is the emperor's son.
그는 황제의 아들이다.
Miss
놓치다
should take a husband.
남편을 맞아야 한다.
That's right.
좋아요.
She should take a husband.
그녀는 남편을 맞이해야 합니다.
Mari.
마리.
did you hear
들었어
They think
그들은 생각한다
only i match you
나만 너랑 어울려
I just heard them say
방금 그들이 말하는 걸 들었어
I should take my husband.
남편을 데려가야겠어요.
As a prince,
왕자로서,
are you willing to marry and live in the Cui Family?
당신은 결혼하여 추이 가문에서 살 의향이 있습니까 ?
♪The sky is full of color♪
♪하늘은 알록달록해요♪
The so-called Prince or King of Qin.
소위 진의 왕자 또는 왕.
I don't want to hold either of these positions and I don't even care.
나는 이 두 가지 직책을 맡고 싶지도 않고 상관하지도 않습니다.
Ying, let's go back to the Laolan Border.
잉, 라오라 국경으로 돌아가자.
We got married there and gave birth to seven or eight children.
우리는 그곳에서 결혼하여 일곱, 여덟 명의 자녀를 낳았습니다 .
Half of them go by your last name.
그들 중 절반은 당신의 성을 따릅니다.
Others go by my last name.
다른 사람들은 내 성을 사용합니다.
I am not married and you are not married.
나는 결혼하지 않았고 당신도 결혼하지 않았습니다.
You don't marry and I don't live in the Cui Residence.
당신은 결혼하지 않고 나는 Cui Residence에 살지 않습니다.
Good?
좋은?
Dream it.
꿈을 꾸세요.
Who wants to give birth to seven or eight children with you?
당신과 함께 일곱, 여덟 명의 아이를 낳고 싶은 사람이 누구입니까 ?
Then, four people.
그럼 4명.
At least four people.
최소 4명.
Two children follow the surname Cui.
두 자녀는 Cui라는 성을 따릅니다.
Others go by the surname Li.
다른 사람들은 Li라는 성을 사용합니다.
What kind of?
어떤 종류의?
If you're bullshitting again,
또 헛소리하면
I will rip your mouth off.
네 입을 찢어버리겠다.
Do you want to tear my mouth?
내 입을 찢고 싶니?
Of.
의.
Dream it.
꿈을 꾸세요.
♪I miss you forever♪
♪영원히 그리워요♪
♪I'm willing to give up this world for you♪
♪나는 당신을 위해 이 세상을 기꺼이 포기하겠습니다 ♪
♪There are no regrets in this life♪
♪이생에 후회는 없다♪
Fear not, Your Highness.
두려워하지 마세요, 전하.
Fifth Han.
다섯번째 그.
It's been so long.
너무 오랜만이에요.
Siege, pursuit, contest of wisdom and courage.
포위, 추격, 지혜와 용기의 경쟁.
You manage to escape every time.
당신은 매번 탈출에 성공합니다.
Fortunately yesterday
다행히 어제
We didn't chase you in Huayang Week on purpose
우리는 일부러 화양주에 당신을 쫓지 않았습니다
so that you remember here is safe
여기가 안전하다는 것을 기억할 수 있도록
and we managed to surround you.
그리고 우리는 당신을 포위했습니다.
Fifth Han.
다섯번째 그.
The governor respects you for your obedience.
주지사는 당신 의 순종을 존중합니다.
As long as you hand over his great-grandson,
그의 증손자를 넘겨주기만 하면
you will not die
당신은 죽지 않을 것이다
Protect his great-grandson even if he dies!
증손자가 죽어도 지켜주세요!
Attack!
공격!
Watch out for Commander Han's back!
한 사령관의 등을 조심하세요!
Fifth Han!
다섯번째 한!
Honourable!
존경스럽습니다!
Go quickly!
빨리 가세요!
Fifth Han!
다섯번째 한!
Road!
도로!
Honourable!
존경스럽습니다!
Fifth Han!
다섯번째 한!
It's useless.
그건 소용 없어.
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
Fifth Han!
다섯번째 한!
Honourable!
존경스럽습니다!
Honourable.
존경스럽습니다.
Fifth Han!
다섯번째 한!
Governor.
지사.
Li Xuanze.
리쉬안쩌.
Say hello to the governor.
주지사님께 인사드립니다.
You're the rebel who killed the emperor!
당신은 황제를 죽인 반역자입니다!
Barbaric!
거친!
Stop!
멈추다!
Don't scare him.
그를 놀라게하지 마십시오.
Han Chang hid you for so long.
한창은 오랫동안 당신을 숨겨왔습니다.
At a critical moment,
중요한 순간에,
he still failed to protect you, didn't he?
그 사람은 아직도 당신을 보호하지 못했어요, 그렇죠?
Even if he obeys,
그 사람이 순종하더라도,
he could not resist the letter of destiny.
그는 운명의 편지에 저항할 수 없었다.
Honourable.
존경스럽습니다.
The letter to the King of Qin has been sent?
진왕에게 보내는 편지를 보냈는가?
Has been sent by speed horse.
스피드 호스로 보내졌습니다.
Don't worry, Your Highness.
걱정하지 마세요, 전하.
King Qin must have tried to save his great-grandson.
진왕은 증손자를 구하려고 노력했을 것입니다.
Although Sun Jin managed to capture his great-grandson,
선진은 증손자를 붙잡는데 성공했지만,
I feel
나는 느낀다
he wouldn't mind his great-grandson so soon.
그는 증손자가 그렇게 빨리 오는 것을 신경 쓰지 않을 것입니다 .
May we still have time to save his great-grandson.
아직 그의 증손자를 구할 시간이 있기를 바랍니다 .
Commander Han has already spoken.
한 사령관은 이미 말했다.
He reorganized the rest of his army.
그는 나머지 군대를 재조직했습니다.
He will try to save his great-grandson as well.
그는 증손자도 구하려고 노력할 것입니다.
His great-grandson is blessed by God.
그의 증손자는 하나님의 축복을 받았습니다.
He will definitely survive.
그는 반드시 살아남을 것이다.
(Dewan Chaoqian)
(드완 차오첸)
Why my lord?
왜요, 주인님?
sent down the order
주문을 보냈습니다
to rebuke King Qin?
진왕을 책망하려고?
Beta ordered him to Changzhou to solve the problem.
베타는 문제를 해결하기 위해 그에게 창저우로 가라고 명령했습니다.
He too
그도 마찬가지
forced beta
강제 베타
bestow the title
칭호를 부여하다
Panglima Besar Weiyang kepada Cui Yi.
Panglima Besar Weiyang kepada Cui Yi.
In fact, he said
사실 그는 이렇게 말했다
the Luoyang clause has become a reality
낙양조항이 현실이 되다
and don't bring it up for a while.
그리고 한동안은 꺼내지 마세요.
Itu Dongdu.
이투 동두.
He considered the affairs of the country
그는 나라의 일을 고려했다
as buying and selling.
사고 파는 것처럼.
He also reported that
그는 또한 다음과 같이 보고했다.
after the Changzhou problem is solved,
창저우 문제가 해결된 후
he and the Cui Family Army
그와 추이 가문 군대
will go to recapture the Tong Border.
통 국경을 탈환하러 갈 것이다.
The Cui Family Army was ambitious.
Cui Family Army는 야심적이었습니다.
What kind of
어떤 종류의
if they colluded
만일 그들이 공모했다면
dengan Sun Jing?
덴간 쑨징?
my lord
군주
This was agreed in a meeting in the seri court.
이것은 세리 법원 회의에서 합의되었습니다 .
Considering Weiyang
웨이양을 고려하다
indeed in Cui Yi's jurisdiction,
실제로 Cui Yi의 관할 구역에서는
It is good that my lord bestowed this title on him.
내 주께서 그에게 이런 칭호를 주신 것은 좋은 일입니다 .
Rumor has it, His Majesty issued an order
소문에 의하면 폐하께서 명령을 내리셨다고 합니다
to rebuke you.
당신을 책망하려고.
I already guessed that your father would reprimand me,
나는 이미 네 아버지가 나를 꾸짖을 것이라고 짐작했다.
but I didn't think this would happen so quickly.
하지만 이 일이 이렇게 빨리 일어날 거라고 는 생각하지 못했습니다 .
Even if you finish
끝내더라도
Changzhou problem without war,
전쟁 없는 창저우 문제,
but the title of Grand Commander of Weiyang was given to someone else.
그러나 웨이양 총사령관의 직함은 다른 사람에게 주어졌습니다.
In fact, you promised not to bring up Luoyang.
사실 당신은 뤄양 이야기를 꺼내지 않겠다고 약속했어요.
Isn't this the title of the trial
이거 재판 제목 아닌가요
to your enemy in the draw?
추첨에서 적에게?
If I were them,
내가 그들이라면,
I will criticize you too.
나도 당신을 비판할 것이다.
You
너
great service in the war.
전쟁에서 훌륭한 봉사.
Most military officers
대부분의 군 장교
in the hall series comes from the Zhenxi Army.
홀 시리즈는 Zhenxi 군대에서 나옵니다.
Of course they will be on your side.
물론 그들은 당신 편이 될 것입니다.
If not,
그렇지 않다면,
you are not just reprimanded.
당신은 단지 질책을 받은 것이 아닙니다.
Instead, your position as King of Qin will be stripped.
대신 진왕의 지위가 박탈될 것입니다.
I do not care.
난 상관 없어.
After all.
결국.
After recapturing the Tong Border,
통국경을 탈환한 후,
I will return to the Laolan Border.
나는 라오라 국경으로 돌아갈 것이다.
It's better than being bullied by people in the draw.
추첨에 참여하는 사람들에게 괴롭힘을당하는 것보다 낫습니다 .
Maybe you can't go back to Laolan Border
어쩌면 당신은 Laolan Border로 돌아갈 수 없을지도 모릅니다.
after recapturing the Tong Border.
통 국경을 탈환한 후.
Not necessarily.
반드시 그런 것은 아닙니다.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
There was an immediate report from Concubine Xiao.
샤오 후궁으로부터 즉각적인 보고가 있었습니다 .
He said, Sun Jing had already held his great-grandson.
그는 손경이 이미 증손자를 안고 있었다고 말했다.
What?
무엇?
Report!
보고서!
Immediate report from the Tong border.
통 국경에서 즉시 보고합니다.
Sun Jing issued a notice of rebellion
Sun Jing은 반란을 선언 했습니다.
at the Tong Border in the name of his great-grandson.
그의 증손자의 이름으로 통 국경에서 .
His great-grandson?
그의 증손자?
Of.
의.
Rebel Sun has found his great-grandson.
Rebel Sun이 증손자를 찾았습니다.
In the notice,
공지사항에는
he criticized...
그는 비판했다...
Talk!
말하다!
He criticized my lord the illegitimate emperor.
그는 내 주를 불법적인 황제라고 비난했습니다.
and called for the army that saved the emperor
그리고 황제를 구한 군대를 소집했습니다
in the name of his great-grandson to eliminate the illegitimate emperor
증손자의 이름으로 불법 황제를 제거하기 위해
so that his great-grandson can ascend the throne.
그의 증손자가 왕위에 오를 수 있도록.
Your father.
아버지.
Since Sun Jing was defeated and withdrew,
손징이 패하고 철수한 이후,
he has no more effort.
그는 더 이상 노력할 필요가 없습니다.
No one knows
아무도 모른다
in case his great-grandson is his real great-great-grandson.
그의 증손자 가 그의 진짜 증손자인 경우.
Patik suggested
Patik이 제안한
we find a boy and claim that he is his great grandson.
우리는 소년을 발견 하고 그가 그의 증손자라고 주장합니다.
No one can distinguish who is his real great-grandson.
그의 진짜 증손자가 누구인지는 누구도 구별할 수 없습니다 .
Honourable,
존경합니다,
Sun Jing dared to issue a notice,
Sun Jing은 감히 통지서를 발행했습니다.
apparently he could prove the boy's identity.
분명히 그는 그 소년의 신원을 증명할 수 있을 것 같습니다.
If we look for a fake great-grandson of his majesty,
폐하의 가짜 증손자를 찾으면
this will be
이것은 ~이 될 것이다
people laugh
사람들은 웃다
and harm us?
그리고 우리에게 해를 끼치나요?
What is Sun Jing's evidence that can prove the boy's identity?
소년 의 신원을 입증 할 수 있는 손징의 증거는 무엇인가 ?
In Sun Jing's notice,
Sun Jing의 공지사항에 따르면,
His great-grandson brought
그의 증손자가 가져온
seal of the late crown prince.
고(故) 황태자의 인장.
my lord
군주
Sun Jing questioned the legitimacy of this kingdom in the name of his great-grandson.
Sun Jing은 증손자의 이름으로 이 왕국의 정당성에 의문을 제기했습니다 .
This is unforgivable.
이것은 용서할 수 없습니다.
Now,
지금,
whether his great-grandson is true or not,
그의 증손자 가 사실인지 아닌지,
we should send an army to fight against Sun Jing,
우리는 Sun Jing과 싸우기 위해 군대를 보내야 합니다 .
restore the Tong Border and his great-grandson.
통 국경과 그의 증손자를 복원하십시오 .
In my opinion,
내 생각에는,
King Qin once recaptured the Tong Border
진왕은 한때 통 국경을 탈환했다.
and fought with Sun Jing repeatedly.
Sun Jing과 반복적 으로 싸웠습니다 .
Furthermore, King Qin proposed to crack down on the Sun Rebels.
게다가 진왕은 태양반군을 진압하자고 제안했다.
So, King of Qin
그래서 진왕(秦王)
the most suitable candidate to go to war.
전쟁에 가장 적합한 후보자 .
In that case, order the King of Qin to lead the army
그렇다면 진왕에게 명령하여 군대를 지휘하게 하라.
go fight the Sun Rebels and recapture the Tong Border.
가서 Sun Rebels 와 싸우고 Tong Border를 탈환하세요.
Doesn't he love to fight?
그 사람은 싸움을 좋아하지 않나요?
This time, he can fight to his heart's content.
이번에는 마음껏 싸울 수 있습니다.
(Boundary Barrel)
(경계 배럴)
Sun Jing issued a notice of rebellion
Sun Jing은 반란을 선언 했습니다.
to delay time on behalf of the military forces attacking Baiyue.
Baiyue를 공격하는 군대를 대신하여 시간을 지연시킵니다 .
Actually, the strength of the army defending the Tong Border is not enough.
사실 통국경을 방어하는 군대의 힘은 턱없이 부족하다.
Do you have a plan?
계획이 있나요?
to take the opportunity to attack into the Tong Border?
통 국경을 공격할 기회를 잡으려면 ?
How do you know that I already have a plan?
나에게 이미 계획이 있다는 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요 ?
It's easy to defend the Tong Border, but it's hard to attack it.
통국경을 방어하기는 쉽지만 공격하기는 어렵다.
However, you once attacked
그러나 당신은 한 번 공격했습니다.
Bind border by force.
강제로 국경을 묶습니다.
Then, quite a while Zhenxi Army
그러다가 꽤 오랫동안 진시군
defending the Tong Border.
통 국경을 방어합니다.
According to your nature,
당신의 성격에 따르면,
you must be watching
당신은보고 있어야합니다
conditions outside and inside the boundary carefully.
경계 외부와 내부의 조건을 주의 깊게 살펴보십시오.
Of.
의.
I left
나는 떠났다
a secret passage in the Tong Border.
통 국경의 비밀 통로.
Secret passage?
비밀통로?
Is it a ditch?
도랑인가요?
How do you know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
The texture of the soil Border Tong is hard.
흙의 질감이 보더통이 딱딱하다.
If you want to dig a tunnel,
터널을 파고 싶다면,
not easy either.
쉽지도 않습니다.
So, this secret passage
그래서 이 비밀 통로는
not newly built.
새로 지은게 아니고.
It has been around for a long time
오랫동안 주변에 있었어
and you can use it.
그리고 당신은 그것을 사용할 수 있습니다.
As I remember, in the Ruijing Year,
내 기억으로는 서경년에
The Tong border was once hit by a flash flood.
통(Tong) 국경은 한때 돌발 홍수를 겪었습니다.
The military armory was flooded with water.
군 무기고는 물에 잠겼습니다.
Then, the Ministry of Finance allocates money
그러면 재무부가 자금을 할당합니다.
to repair the ditch.
도랑을 수리하기 위해.
The ditch was quite deep and wide.
도랑은 꽤 깊고 넓었다.
It feels like people can move inside.
사람들이 안으로 들어갈 수 있을 것 같은 느낌이에요.
You know about
당신은에 대해 알고
the affairs of the Ministry of Finance in the Year of Ruijing?
서경년 재무부의 업무는 ?
Childhood,
어린 시절,
I like to read with my father.
나는 아버지와 함께 책을 읽는 것을 좋아합니다.
In his reading room,
그의 독서실에는
besides books about the military,
군대에 관한 책 외에도
there are also many files
파일도 많아요
about repairs
수리에 대해
which is conducted at all borders.
이는 모든 국경에서 실시됩니다.
I read it as a story book.
동화책으로 읽었네요.
I remember it after reading.
읽고 나면 기억이 나네요.
Tonight...
오늘 밤...
Tonight, King of Qin
오늘밤, 진왕
will be rats that infiltrate the ditch.
도랑에 침투하는 쥐가 될 것입니다 .
Of course I have to accompany you.
물론 나도 동행해야 한다.
I will await your instructions outside the city.
나는 도시 밖에서 당신의 지시를 기다리겠습니다 .
♪If you've forgotten the twinkling light♪
♪반짝이는 빛을 잊으셨다면♪
♪Tunggu kenangan♪
♪퉁구 케난간♪
♪Shattered and sunk♪
♪부서져 가라앉았어♪
♪The spots that remain on your heart♪
♪당신의 마음속에 남아있는 얼룩들 ♪
♪Penarikan itu♪
♪페나리칸 이투♪
♪It's my objection♪
♪이의가 있어요♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪그리움이 결코 버리지 않는다면♪
♪Longing to go back to the earliest times♪
♪ 가장 옛날로 돌아가고 싶은 그리움 ♪
♪The warmth that fate once had♪
♪운명이 가졌던 따뜻함 ♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪당신을 위해 간직하고 싶어요♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪We once promised♪
♪한번 약속했었지♪
♪Even though love hurts me♪
♪사랑이 나를 아프게 해도♪
♪I must live for you too♪
♪나도 당신을 위해 살아야 해요♪
♪Following faces in memories♪
♪추억 속 얼굴을 따라가다♪
♪Waiting is my obsession♪
♪기다리는 것이 나의 집착♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪